#### Komlan ZANKPE

Senior DevOps Engineer

#### **Profiles**

kzankpe

Summary

k <u>kzalikpe</u>

</> me.kzankpe.com

automation. At MEGA, I have defined the **DevOps strategy** to drive innovation and accelerate delivery. Laid the foundation to develop and deploy multi-tenant SaaS application. Beyond my technical expertise, I was the **primary advocate** for DevOps principles at the R&D leadership level.

DevOps Engineer with over 8 years of experience in designing, implementing infrastructure, CI/CD and

#### Experience

Mega International Lead DevOps July 2022 - Present

Paris (FRANCE)

https://www.mega.com/

Software company with solutions for Enterprise Architecture, Governance, Business Process Analysis, Data Intelligence etc...

- Directed the cultural change by defining the DevOps strategy for the R&D
- Mentored a team of three engineers and improved team productivity
- Designed Azure landing zone for applications deployed to IaaS/PaaS
   Introduced more automation, tools and processes to ease products lifecycle and accelerate delivery: CI/CD with
- Azure DevOps, Pull Requests, Infra as Code with **Terraform**.
- Enforced **best practices** to ensure consistency and compliance

## Thales Services Numeriques DevOps Engineer

June 2021 - June 2022

Velizy

Company specialized in the design, development and maintenance of secure Information Systems.

Orange Bussines Services, within the Azure practice:
Contributed to the design and implementation of the Landing Zone with Terraform

- Implemented hybrid cloud architecture with Azure Arc
- Migrated workload to cloud using Azure Services Recovery
- On premises infrastructure assessment with **Azure Migrate**

#### Neocase Software Cloud DevOps Engineer

November 2018 - June 2021 La Garenne Colombes

A leading provider of integrated HR and Finance service delivery solutions.

At the core of Cloud and Security team, leading the automation work to cut down delivery time:

- Migrated applications to Azure (Lift and Shift)
- Automated deployment with PowerShell scripts
- ARM templates and **DSC** used to build Infrastructure as Code
- Monitored client's application with ELK stack
   Developed custom PowerShell module for application administration

## Ariane Systems Technical Implementation Manager

June 2016 - October 2018

A company providing online check-in/out technologies to the hotel industry.

Pantin (FRANCE)

Within the project team and collaborating with the development team:

## Infrastructure management: deployment and management of azure resources

- Deploy client environments using webservices
- Advanced technical support on the applicationsWrote training documentation and guidelines

#### **Arelis Group** Field Service Engineer

February 2014 - March 2016 Colombes

Specialized in design and integration of electronic solutions

Working with the 2nd Authority for Television and Radio (Jerusalem). Broadcasting DVBT and DVBT2 signal in Israel:

## Installation and maintenance of RF transmitters

Network monitoringStorage and resources management

**Telecommunication Engineering** 

- Ensure client's expectations were satisfied
- Education

## Institut Supérieur D'Electronique De Paris

#### <u> ♦ https://en.isep.fr/</u>

Master's

**Positive Attitude** 

September 2009 - September 2012

Signal processing, Wireless networks, Electronics, Digital communications, Web development ...

Projects
Platform Engineering

#### $Create\ an\ Internal\ Developer\ Platform\ using\ the\ open-source\ tools\ available:\ Backstage,\ Azure\ DevOps/GitHub,$

### Terraform etc...

Agile Methodology

Soft Skills

Teamwork

Continuous

Improvement

**Technical Skills** 

Cloud Management	CI/CD (Azure	Configuration	<b>Version Control (Git)</b>	Terraform
(Azure)	DevOps/GitHub)	management	• • • • 0	• • • • 0
••••	• • • • 0	(Ansible/DSC)		
		• • • • •		
PowerShell	ARM Template/	Golang/Python	Windows Server/IIS	MSSQL Server
••••	Bicep	••••	• • • 0 0	• • • 0 0
	• • • • •			
SonarCloud	Unix/Linux	Docker/kubernetes	Grafana/Prometheus	API/Postman
• • • 0 0	• • • 0 0	• • • 0 0	• • • 0 0	• • 0 0 0
Certifications				

# **Az-104: Microsoft Azure Administrator**Microsoft

February 2021

November 2020

**Az-400: Designing and Implementing Microsoft DevOps Solutions** Microsoft

Microsoft

AZ-305: Designing Microsoft Azure Infrastructure Solutions

**Critical Thinking** 

March 2022

Languages

French

English
• • • • •